There are tons of APIs available on the web
يوجد عدد كبير من واجهات برمجة التطبيقات على الويب
that readily serve up interesting information.
التي تُقدم معلومات مهمة بسهولة.
And they're usually free to use,
وعادة ما تكون مجانية الاستخدام،
so long as you aren't making thousands of requests per hour.
إلا إذا كنت تقوم بعمل آلاف الطلبات في الساعة.
For instance, Google offers a ton of APIs,
وكمثال، يوفر Google عددًا كبيرًا من واجهات برمجة التطبيقات،
including Google Analytics, Google Maps, Google Fonts.
شاملةً Google Analytics، Google Maps، Google Fonts.
Looking around the Web,
بالبحث في الويب،
it isn't hard to find examples of websites that use
ليس من الصعب إيجاد أمثلة لمواقع الويب التي تستخدم
external API to create interesting interactions for users.
واجهة برمجة تطبيقات خارجية لإنشاء تفاعلات شيقة للمستخدمين.
Reddit and the Reddit Enhancement Suite Chrome plugin
يتفاعل Reddit والمكوّن الإضافي Reddit Enhancement Suite Chrome
interact with a few different APIs to make Reddit feel more dynamic.
مع بعض واجهات برمجة تطبيقات مختلفة ليكون Reddit أكثر ديناميكية.
When a user clicks on a link that resolves to a YouTube video,
عندما ينقر المستخدم فوق رابط يحل فيديو YouTube،
Reddit opens up an embedded YouTube player which interacts with the YouTube API.
يفتح Reddit مشغل YouTube المضمّن الذي يتفاعل مع YouTube API.
Or when a user opens up a link to a Twitter feed,
أو عندما يفتح المستخدم رابط موجز Twitter،
the Reddit Enhancement Suite Chrome plugin fires off an Ajax request for
يُطلق المكّون الإضافي Reddit Enhancement Suite Chrome طلب Ajax
Twitter data and uses the Twitter API to open up the tweet right here inside the page.
لبيانات Twitter ويستخدم Twitter API لفتح التغريدة هنا مباشرةً داخل الصفحة.
Check out the link in the instructor notes if
افحص الرابط في ملاحظات المعلّم إذا كنت
you want to find some more APIs that are available.
ترغب في إيجاد بعض واجهات برمجة التطبيقات الأخرى المتاحة.